# **RÉSUMÉ**

Eric Daniel Fournier

February 8, 2018

Email: me@ericdfournier.com Mobile: +1 310 746 6925 Web: www.ericdfournier.com

### Introduction

I have dedicated my entire professional life to the pursuit of knowledge that is relevant to some of our species' most pressing environmental challenges. In the course of this pursuit I have developed considerable expertise in the use of various information technologies for the purposes of documenting, analyzing, and simulating environmental systems. My overarching goal is to have the opportunity to share these skills within a community of gifted individuals who are all unified in their determination to effect meaningful environmental change.

#### Education

Doctor of Philosophy	2010-2015
Bren School of Environmental Science & Management, UCSB	
Master of Arts	2013-2015
Geography Department, UCSB	
Master of Environmental Science	2008-2010
School of Forestry & Environmental Science, Yale University	
Bachelor of Science	2004-2008
Environmental Science Department, Bucknell University	

## Experience

Post-Doctoral Researcher	2016-Present
Institute for the Environment & Sustainability, UCLA	
Graduate Student Researcher	2013-2015
Earth Research Institute, UCSB	
Teaching Assistant	2009-2013
Bren School of Environmental Science & Management, UCSB	
Yale School of Forestry & Environmental Science, Yale University	

#### **Publications**

- [1] Eric D Fournier, Arturo A Keller, Roland Geyer, and James Frew. Investigating the Energy-Water Usage Efficiency of the Reuse of Treated Municipal Wastewater for Artificial Groundwater Recharge. Environmental Science & Technology, 50(4):2044–2053, Jan 2016.
- [2] Eric D Fournier. MOGADOR revisited: Improving a genetic approach to multi-objective corridor search. Environment and Planning B: Planning and Design, 43(4):663–680, Dec 2015.
- [3] Arturo A Keller, Eric D Fournier, and Jessica Fox. Minimizing impacts of land use change on ecosystem services using multi-criteria heuristic analysis. Journal of Environmental Management, 156(0):23–30, June 2015.
- [4] Rose B Merola, Eric D Fournier, and Molly M McGuire. Spectroscopic investigations of Fe2+ complexation on nontronite clay. Langmuir, 23(3):1223–1226, Jan 2007.